<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Things I want | tushman.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://jtushman.github.io/blog/categories/things-i-want/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jtushman.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-16T09:21:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jtushman.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jonathan Tushman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailing It In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jtushman.github.io/blog/2013/05/17/mailing-it-in/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-17T12:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jtushman.github.io/blog/2013/05/17/mailing-it-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>File this under, something I want, but not going to build &hellip;</p>

<p>Had another idea in the shower this morning (all of my ideas happen in the shower).</p>

<p><strong>Problem Statement:</strong>  What is an easy, non stressful way to communicate what we are working on cross coasts.  And for me the most important aspect of that is <strong>what are people struggling with</strong>, and does someone else on our growing team have knowledge to help them.</p>

<p>For example.  I was working to set up flower to monitor celery.  I mentioned that to Marc, and he said, &ldquo;I had a really bad experience with that.  It caused a pretty significant memory loss&rdquo;.  Really good to know.</p>

<p>There a bunch of tools out there, some that we use, and some that we don&rsquo;t, that solve parts of the problem:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.pivotaltracker.com">Pivotal Tracker</a>:  What am I currently working on</li>
<li><a href="http://www.github.com">GitHub</a>:  What changes have I made to the code base(s)</li>
<li><a href="https://idonethis.com/">IDoneThis</a>: (we don&rsquo;t use this)  But it is a cool (but IMHO overpriced) tool that you simply email a quick email on what you did today.</li>
</ol>


<p>My idea I am calling <strong>Mailing It In™</strong>.  This is what I want it to do:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Everyday you send a <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">markdown</a> formated email to <a href="&#109;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x69;&#x74;&#105;&#110;&#x40;&#x7a;&#x65;&#x66;&#x72;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#109;&#x2e;">&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x69;&#116;&#105;&#x6e;&#64;&#x7a;&#101;&#x66;&#x72;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#x6d;&#46;</a>  I need to think about this more, but I think we just need to answer two questions:</p>

<ol>
<li>What am I struggling with:</li>
<li>I learned this cool thing:</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>What you are working on will be automatically taken out of pivotal</p></li>
<li>At Noon every day an digest email will be sent out to the entire team (similar to the daily scrum)</li>
<li>A weekly summery digest email can also be configured</li>
<li>All of this content will be posted in  a Jekyl blog hosted internally at ZEFR.  This site will have the following features (most coming for free from <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyl</a> or <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>):

<ol>
<li>Search</li>
<li>Be able to see history by team, person, company</li>
<li>Have <a href="http://disqus.com/">disqus</a> integrated</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Anyways &mdash; just an idea.  Not going to do anything about it besides write this post.  But if someone develops it &mdash; Let me know!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
